# **JUSTIN MCKENDRY**

San Francisco, CA, USA

Languages: Native American & French (US & French Citizenships)

**2** + 33 7 67 39 14 79 justmckendry@hotmail.com

www.justinmckendry.com

#### **Profile**

Self-taught ecommerce and digital advertising graduate aiming to empower businesses' front operations. Proud owner of 6-digit offline & online businesses in the F&B & clothing industry across 20 countries. I aim to leverage on my entrepreneurial experience to help to provide insightful reviews, perspectives, and directions on business strategies and operational performance. Experience extends to higher level projects in digital strategy inside 2 consulting companies: mobile app creation, marketplace micro-service implementation, A/B testing PR advertising & social media data mining & scraping.

- Business owner of 2 profitable businesses
- Passionate online merchandiser
- Customer obsessed SEM Growth Hacker

- Sales enabler optimizing use of data & information
- Hybrid analyst with SQL & Python based projects
- Strategy consulting background & work ethic

# **Professional Experiences**

Hypestore, Co-Founder (CPG - SaaS B2B2C)

02/2018 - Now

- Auto check-out bot aiming a wide-range of G&S in shortage online to create EU 1st street-wear reselling marketplace
- Test driven development on weekly online drops, bot captcha bypass, scrum strategy & pricing, peer-coding

Actility, Freelance Business Strategy Consultant (IoT LPWAN leader - #Minicorn (100M€ MV)

08/2017 - 09/2017

- IoT LPWAN market sizing, automatic reporting internal setup, B2B SEA, tree structure & UX simplification
- Consistent 1st SERP for EU IoT based searches, CTR 2.68% (+12% MoM), +6% conversion rate in € in 1 month

Capgemini Consulting, Junior digital consultant (Digital strategy consulting)

01/2017 - 08/2017

- "As is, to be" marketplace assessment & best practices, co-created commercial proposals, project scoping & sales deck
- Data mining & market research, initiated & lead competitor surveillance program (Alipay, WechatPay)
- Creating company's 1st data scraping bootcamp & online merchandiser training, 1st junior showcasing banking mobile app

Locura, Co-Founder (CPG brand & company) https://www.locurashop.com/

11/2016 - 03/2018

- Sourcing & merchandising new brand on Chinese ecommerce ecosystem (Taobao, 1688.com, Alibaba)
- Managed SEM, import-export, customs, cash model, inventory & data management, self-learning pricing, website creation
- Stock-out in 5 months (66K€ GMV), advised & trained client BMs (Vilebrequin, Hermes JV, Tegoya...), +21% QoQ GMV

Fast up partners, Junior digital consultant & E-commerce BM (Digital strategy consulting)

05/2016 - 12/2016

- Business audit, market research, A/B testing FB ads, Amazon competition activity monitoring, retail analytics based on crowdsourcing, cold call & brand manager for US & Chinese clients on marketplace deployment, SEM, EU fiscal aid.
- Signed 1st US Client & successfully launched on Amazon (120k/year GMV), PR campaign (3k reactions/publication)

Secrets fine food, Associate (Gourmet retailer - Singapore)

01/2016 - 04/2017

- Accounting & financial reporting & forecasting, SKU profit based rotation, (Insta & Facebook creation). In-store sales.
- 4 months break-even, 600k\$/year

# **Education**

#### HEC Montreal, Bachelor in Business administration (B.A.A),

Graduating April 30th 2018

- Major: Finance
- Exchange in Singapore management university (SMU) (GPA > 3,5)

January 2016 – May 2016

International Baccalaureate (IB) - Economics & Science, Lycée International Honoré de Balzac

June 2013

# Other experiences

- CFA research challenge (03/2018): Conducting an Equity Research Report for Canada Dollar store leader 2<sup>nd</sup> Regional
- TMX simulation, Options trading competition (12/2017) 2<sup>nd</sup> place at HEC
- Project identity", Singapore (06/2016): Research and outreach initiative on national identity in Singapore
- HEC Consulting club, Montréal (12/2015): Managing mandate on continuing vocational training BCG's training program
- AIESEC Corporate relations Director (05-12/2015: Sales of AIESEC GIP, signed 2 TNs. Designated best CR member
- Model United Nations (HDBMUN) Co-founder, (01-2015): Raised 35k€, 400 students, 5 countries, Elected MVP

#### IT skills:

Bloomberg, Salesforce, Postico, Adobe suite, Facebook Ad, Alexa.com, Lengow, Mirakl, Boxshot, Keepa, junglescout, marvel, real time board, Google suite (analytics, tag manager, data studio,...): Html, wordpress, Very basic knowledge in python & SQL